# Ratish Udawat

### Full Stack Engineer & JavaScript Enthusiast

Full Stack Engineer with over 6 years of experience in building and maintaining complex web applications. Demonstrated expertise in architecting, designing, and implementing solutions across the entire develop work@ratishu.com

(+91) 82332-23898

ratishu.com

linkedin.com/in/ratishudawat in

github.com/ratishudawat 🕡

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Software Engineer

**Unify Technologies** 

07/2022 - Present

Client: Harman International

Bengaluru, IN

- Designed and implemented high-performance UIs using React, Typescript, Node.js AG-Grid and Tanstack capable of managing up to 1 million logs efficiently.
- Integrated Harman's automotive tool with DLT parsing and realtime hardware logging using TypeScript, C++, Qt, Electron, and Eclipse Theia resulting in 30% faster debugging and 25% improved data logging accuracy.
- Successfully handling a high frequency of unified logs, and enhancing system performance by 30%.
- Recognized as the "Star Performer for Q1-2023" for exceptional contributions.

### Software Engineer

Altimetrik

10/2020 - 09/2021

Bengaluru, IN

Client: PayPal

- Achieved a 50% ramp in tech stack migration for the PayPal Activities component using React, Node and Kubernetes.
- Successfully driven the GoPay-Paypal integration for China data centres using Dust.is & Java.

# **Software Engineer** HolidayIQ

08/2018 - 08/2020

Bengaluru, IN

- Created a tracking engine from scratch using Express and handlebars to generate custom reports on user engagement.
- Developed a dynamic chat form using React, Node.js, MySQL, Docker, Kafka, and Elasticsearch, boosting daily leads by 20%.

## Full Stack Developer

Vaahika

03/2017 - 04/2018

Jaipur, IN

- Created a Node.js and Handlebars dashboard, enhancing client interaction and reducing support queries by 30%, leveraging MySQL and AWS (S3, EC2).
- Designed and integrated robust APIs for the Android application, improving data synchronization speed by 40% and user engagement by 25%.

### **SKILLS**



### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Redhat Openstack(6.0 Mitaka)

Linux World Informatics Pvt Ltd

Redhat Certified Engineer (RHCE v7)

Linux World Informatics Pvt Ltd

#### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech, Computer Science Engineering Rajasthan Technical University (2013-2017)

 Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Databases, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Advance Data Structures and Algorithms, Information Retrieval, Image Processing

### LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### **HOBBIES**

Football Travel Fitness